

Bhagya Nirmani

Passionate front-end developer with 6+ years of overall experience in software development is eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent communication skills. Proven experience in developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux and Java 8+. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases. Fast at learning and mastering new technologies; working successfully in both team and self-directed settings.



Colombo, Sri Lanka in 😱 🖹







Work Experience



Senior Software Engineer (React) · Lassana Group of Companies

January 2023 - Present

- -Developing responsive and cross-browser websites from UI/UX Design, including various functionalities and design implementation, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- -Collaborating with design team members to implement new features and improve website functionality.
- -Identified and resolved website performance issues to ensure optimal user experience.

Lassana.com is a leading e-commerce company and the most trusted online premium gift delivery service in Sri Lanka.



Software Engineer (ReactJs) · Lassana Group of Companies

March 2022 - January 2023

- -Created various CSS and JS animations to enhance the user experience.
- -Developed responsive and cross-browser pages from UI/UX Design to deployment using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and Redux.
- -Collaborated with design team members to implement new features and improve the website functionality.
- -Identified and resolved website performance issues to ensure optimal user experience.
- -Improved site speed through optimization of images and reduction of HTTP requests.



Software Engineer • Kaleris

July 2018 - February 2019

- -Shipxpress (A Kaleris company) was a GE Transportation company and was later merged with Wabtec in February 2019.
- -Troubleshooting technical issues in server-side developments involving java/spring implementations.
- -Proficiently collaborated with multinational teams in USA and India.
- -Worked closely with business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high quality products as a Software Engineer.
- -Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements, budget and product goal.
- -Working in a Scrum Team and practicing all major scrum ceremonies and following agile methodologies.



Associate Software Engineer • SYNERGEN Health

February 2017 - March 2018

- Worked as a backend software engineer Java/JEE in two projects; Synergen Billing Interface

and SynegenPay Platform.

- Implemented a producer consumer pattern as part of the project implementation.

Troubleshooted issues in the code base and fixed bugs reported by QA engineers.



Software Developer • IFS

December 2014 - December 2016

- Worked as a software engineer in North America Consulting team providing customization and maintenance support for IFS ApplicationsTM .
- Received company training C#, .NET Framework, PLSQL
- Experienced in PLSQL, Centura
- Job responsibilities included analyzing functional specifications, preparing designs and developing customizations, performing technical investigations, installing RND patches and Standard bug fixes, creating and sending

deliveries of patches and customizations to customers.

Education



2017 - 2019

University of Colombo School of Computing

PGDip, Computer Science



2010 - 2014

University of Moratuwa

Bachelor of Science , Information Technology

Skills

- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- HTML
- CSS
- Java

Languages

• English — Professional

Powered by CakeResume